Lovestone, Jay Papers 6036/028
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Jay Lovestone Papers
1929-1983
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Lovestone, Jay
6036/028
7 cubic feet
7 linear ft.
Papers.
This collection contains correspondence, speeches, writings, reports, and collected material of Jay Lovestone, primarily documenting his interest and work in international labor affairs in the 1960s and 1970s.
5770072
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 22, 2003
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 30, 2015
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Jay Lovestone was born on December 24, 1898 in Lithuania, which was then a part of Russia. His father obtained a job in a New York synagogue and Lovestone came with his family to the U.S. at the age of 9. He graduated from City College in 1918 and soon found himself involved in the Socialist and Communist movements. Lovestone became a founding member of the American Communist Party in 1919, and became editor of the Communist Party publication "The Communist" in 1921. Lovestone led the party from 1927 until his expulsion in 1929. Lovestone and his followers formed the Communist Party of the United States, later the Independent Labor League of America, but more commonly known as the "Lovestonites," which disbanded in 1940. In 1943, Lovestone was appointed the founding director of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' (ILGWU) International Affairs Department. He went on to serve as Secretary of the Free Trade Union Committee, director of the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions, and director of the AFL-CIO's Department of International Affairs, serving from 1963 until his retirement in 1974. Lovestone died on March 7, 1990 at the age of 91.
Scope and Contents
The collection is divided into six series: Correspondence, Foreign Files, Speeches, Writings and Reports, Miscellaneous, Personal Paraphernalia, and Financial Documents. Spanning Lovestone's work as the Director of the ILGWU's International Relations Department, as well as Director of the AFL-CIO's Department of International Affairs, these papers include correspondence with individuals and organizations with considerable interest in the growth of trade unionism abroad. The Correspondence Series consists of general correspondence, files, and documents that are arranged alphabetically by either individual or organization. This series occupies the bulk of the collection. It includes correspondence to and from Lovestone, as well as clippings and articles. The individuals and organizations contained within the correspondence reflects the international nature of Lovestone's work, including material to and from Europe, Africa, and Asia, while not all of the material is in English. There is correspondence to both national and international organizations, as well as the U. S. Department of Labor and the State Department. Individuals that Lovestone communicated with include consulate generals, diplomats, labor attaches, labor leaders (both national and international), senators, and congressmen. There is substantial information from organization of which Lovestone was involved, including the AFL-CIO and The Atlantic Council of the United States (of which Lovestone was a director). Notable individuals in the collection that Lovestone communicated with include Irving Brown (International Confederation of Free Trade Unions representative to the U.N.), Harry Goldberg (Department of International Affairs at the AFL-CIOletters and reports regarding missions to various countries), Dale Good (labor attach at the United States Embassy in Germany), Fritz Heine (senior figure in the German Social Democratic Party), Lane Kirkland, George Meany, Walter Reuther, Bayard Rustin, and Philip Taft, and important ILGWU leaders such as Sol Chaikin, David Dubinsky, Roy Godson, Mark Staar, Louis Stulberg, and Charles Zimmerman.
The remaining series contain foreign files which contain reports, notes from trips to various countries regarding delegation visits, and reports that were written and compiled by individuals and sent back to Lovestone; speeches presented at conferences and meetings as well as drafts of chapters and reports; general reports, many to the Free Trade Union Committee of the Labor League for Human Rights, of which Lovestone was executive secretary, as well as "News from the AFL-CIO" and a typed copy of Theodore Draper's "The Roots of American Communism"; notes business cards and collected letters and documents; and receipts, invoices, and expense reports.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/014: ILGWU Local 22, Charles S. Zimmerman Papers 5780/062: ILGWU International Relations Department Records 6036/023: Jay Lovestone Interview by E. Finn
Arrangement
Series I. Correspondence
Series II. Foreign Files
Series III. Speaches, Writings, and Reports
Series IV. Miscellaneous
Series V. Personal Paraphenalia
Series VI. Financial Documents
Lovestone, Jay.; Angelton, James.; Beichman, Arnold.; Brombart, David.; Bruegel, John.; Bundy, Eldridge.; Coste, Brutus.; Dan, Phan-Quang.; Dohrn, Klaus.; Dubinsky, David, -- 1892-1982.; Eivan, Amos.; Jackson, Henry M. -- (Henry Martin), -- 1912-1983.; Kethley, Anna.; Meany, George, -- 1894-; Mihajlov, Mihajlo, -- 1934-2010.; Paladino, Morris.; Reuther, Walter, -- 1907-1970.; Riesel, Victor.; Shanker, Albert.; Taft, Philip, -- 1902-1976.; Tehas, Virginia.; Thieman, Elfrieda.; Weiner, Herbert E., -- 1921-; Wittfogel, Karl.; Zimmerman, Charles S., -- 1896-1983.; AFL-CIO. -- Executive Council.; Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace.
5770072
- Series I. Correspondence
  - A (General Correspondence), 1952-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AFL-CIO Executive Council, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Angleton, James, 1976-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Atlantic Council of the U.S., 1972-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Atlantic Council (Theodore Achilles), June-December 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - B (General Correspondence), 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - B (General Correspondence) April-June 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - B (General Correspondence) June-October 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - B (General Correspondence) October-December 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - B (General Correspondence) January-June 1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - B (General Correspondence) June-December 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - B (General Correspondence) December-January 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - B (General Correspondence), 1969-1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - B (General Correspondence), 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Barth, Hans, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Beichman, Arnold, 1967-1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bergeron, Andre, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Barochowitz, Elly, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Barochowitz, Elly, 1968-1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Brandel, Kuno, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Brandel, Kuno, 1968-1975 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Brombart, David, 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Brown, Irving, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Bruegel, John, 1967-1977 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Bruegel, John, 1967-1977 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Bruegel, John, 1967-1977 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Bruegel, John, 1967-1977 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Bruegel, John, 1967-1977 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Bundy, Eldridge, 1965-1977 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - C (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 1, Folder 45a)
  - Chaikin, Sol C., 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Chudnovsky, David, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Coste, Brutus, 1967-1977 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Cueno, Ernes, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - D (General Correspondence), 1963-1983 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Dan, Phan-Quang, 1970-1981 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Das, Mohan, 1969-1980 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - DAulay, Jacques, 1972-1982 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Delaney, George, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Doherty, William C. Jr., 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Dohrn, Klaus, 1969-1977 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Dohrn, Klaus, 1969-1977 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Dohrn, Klaus, 1969-1977 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Dohrn, Klaus, 1969-1977 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Dohrn, Klaus, 1969-1977 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Dubinsky, David, 1946-1974 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - E (General Correspondence), 1963-1980 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - E (General Correspondence), 1963-1980 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - E (General Correspondence), 1963-1980 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Eckstein, Viola, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Economist, The, 1968-1982 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Eivan, Amos, 1968-1981 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - F (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - F (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - F (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - F (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - F (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Feather, Victor, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Feldman, Paul, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Fever, Lewis, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Finlay, Murray H., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Foreign Policy Research Institute, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Fox, John D., 1982 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Freedom House, 1967-1972 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Frontlash, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - G (General Correspondence), 1963-1969 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - G (General Correspondence), 1963-1969 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - G (General Correspondence), 1963-1969 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - G (General Correspondence), 1963-1969 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - G (General Correspondence), 1969-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - G (General Correspondence), 1969-1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Gershman, Carl, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Gerstemaier, Cornelia, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Gleason, Thomas, 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Godson, Joseph, 1967-1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Godson, Joseph, 1967-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Godson, Roy, 1968-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Goldberg, Harry, 1967-1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Goldberg, Harry, 1967-1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Goldberg, Harry, 1967-1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Goldberg, Harry, 1967-1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Goldberg, Harry, 1967-1974 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Goldberg, Harry, 1967-1974 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Goldberg, Harry, 1967-1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Good, Dale, 1969-1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Good, Dale, 1969-1982 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Good, Dale, 1969-1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Goott, Daniel, 1969-1975 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - H (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - H (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - H (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - H (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Haig, Alexander, 1975-1981 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Heine, Fritz, 1967-1983 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Heine, Fritz, 1967-1983 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Heine, Fritz, 1967-1983 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Heine, Fritz, 1967-1983 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Heitman, Sidney, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Hertz, Paul, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Hillenbrand, George, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Hoover Institute, 1973-1983 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Hoover Institute, 1973-1983 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - I (General Correspondence), 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - I.L.G.W.U., 1971 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - J (General Correspondence), 1963-1981 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - J (General Correspondence), 1963-1981 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Jackson, Henry M., 1968-1977 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Jackson, Henry M., 1968-1977 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Jackson, Henry M., 1968-1977 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - K (General Correspondence), 1963-1982 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - K (General Correspondence), 1963-1982 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - K (General Correspondence), 1963-1982 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - K (General Correspondence), 1963-1982 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Kallmertin, Werner, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Kethley, Anna, 1967-1976 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Kirkland, Lane, 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Kirkland, Lane, 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Kirkland, Lane, 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Kirkland, Lane, 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Kirkland, Lane, 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Kirkland, Lane, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Kirkland, Lane, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - L (General Correspondence), 1950-1980 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Lassner, Franz, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Leber, George, 1975-1981 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Lee, Ernest, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1952-1960 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    Scope and Contents
    April-May
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    June-October
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Lovestone, Jay, 1961-1983 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - M (General Correspondence), 1963-1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - M (General Correspondence), 1963-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - M (General Correspondence), 1963-1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - M (General Correspondence), 1963-1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - McLellan, Andrew, 1969-1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Malley, Simon, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Malley, Simon, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Mandel, Ben, 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Matal, Karl, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Matal, Karl, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Matal, Karl, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Matal, Karl, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Meany, George, 1960-1975 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Mihajlov, Mihajlo, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Mihajlov, Mihajlo, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Moghrabi, Zuhayr A., 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Montana, Vanni, 1969-1977 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Montana, Vanni, 1969-1977 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Montana, Vanni, 1969-1977 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Moore, Walden, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Morris, Robert (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Morse, David, 1947-1953 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Morse, David, 1947-1953 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Murphy, Robert, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - N (General Correspondence), 1969-1975 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - N (General Correspondence), 1969-1975 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Nagy, Ernest A., 1976-1983 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - O (General Correspondence), 1967-1975 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Osner Business Machines, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - P (General Correspondence), 1962-1981 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - P (General Correspondence), 1962-1981 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - P (General Correspondence), 1962-1981 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Paladino, Morris, 1970-1977 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Pansky, Miroslav, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Pansky, Miroslav, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Pansky, Miroslav, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Pansky, Miroslav, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Pendley, Robert, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Pollack, Harry, 1970-1975 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Q (General Correspondence), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Qassim, Y., 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - R (General Correspondence), 1963-1981 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Radio Free Europe, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - A. Phillip Randolph Institute, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1962-1983 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1962-1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1962-1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1962-1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1962-1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1962-1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1962-1983 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1962-1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1962-1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1962-1983 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1962-1983 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1962-1983 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1962-1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Riesel, Victor, 1966-1983 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Riesel, Victor, 1966-1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Rostow, Eugene, 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Rowney, Edward, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Rozek, Edward, 1976-1983 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Rozek, Edward, 1976-1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Ruane, Rosemary, 1975-1982 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Ruhnau, Heinz, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Rustin, Bayard, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - S (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - S (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - S (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - S (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - S (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - S (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - S (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - S (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - S (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Sanders, Sol, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Scalapino, Robert A (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Schauff, Johannes, 1970-1974 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Schiller, Leonard, 1970-1975 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Schiller, Leonard, 1970-1975 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Schlesinger, James, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Schurr, Sam and Bea, 1975-1983 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Shanker, Albert, 1972-1981 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Shelepin, Alexander, 1967-1971 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Speigal, Der, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Staar, Richard F., 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Stack, Wally, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Stack, Wally, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Stack, Wally, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Stulberg, Louis, 1960-1975 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Sullivan, William, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Sussman, Leonard, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Svitak, Ivan, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Svitak, Ivan, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Svitak, Ivan, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Szenajch, Alexander, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - T (General Correspondence), 1967-1982 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - T (General Correspondence), 1967-1982 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - T (General Correspondence), 1967-1982 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - T (General Correspondence), 1967-1982 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - T (General Correspondence), 1967-1982 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Taft, Phillip, 1970-1976 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Taft, Phillip, 1970-1976 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Tehas, Virginia, 1967-1980 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Thieman, Elfrieda, 1970-1981 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Thieman, Elfrieda, 1970-1981 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Thierens, Jeanne, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - U (General Correspondence), 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - UAW, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - United Nations, 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - USIA, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - V (General Correspondence), 1969-1980 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Vetter, Heinz O., 1969-1976 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Vetter, Heinz O., 1969-1976 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Vetter, Heinz O., 1969-1976 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - W (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - W (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - W (General Correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Warnock, John A., 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Weiner, Herbert E., 1967-1983 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Weiner, Herbert E., 1967-1983 (Box 4, Folder 78)